SYSTEM ENGINEER/NETWORK ENGINEER

Summary

A self-motivated and self-learning IT professional with more than 10 years in consulting, engineering and deploying of computer infrastructure. \hat{A} I have a strong urge to understand how computer systems work in order to better utilize and manage them. \hat{A} Expertise in engineering and maintain complex server and network environments. I have a strong desire to work with other in order to design and maintain efficient and productive computer systems.

â€∢

Software Experience

- Linux and other Unix based Distributions
- Windows OS (all versions)
- Windows Server OS (2003/2008/2012/2016)
- Mac OSX
- Office 365 (AD synced/Hybrid)
- Exchange 2007/2010/2013
- SharePoint 2010/2013/O365
- · Active Directory
- DNS Servers (Microsoft/BINDs)

- AWS (EC2, S3, VPC)
- VMsphere/ESXi
- Xen Server
- Hyper-V
- Software Based VOIP
- SQL Databases (MSSQL/MYSQL)
- Common Network Tools
- Backup Imaging Software (VSS and file based)
- Remote Desktop (Single and RDP Farm)

Networking

- VPN: IPSEC, PPTP, SSL, OpenVPN
- **Protocols**: TCP/IP, NetBIOS, PPP, HTTP, FTP, SMTP/POP3/IMAP/, LDAP, SNMP, SSH, SMB/CIFS, SSL (Certificates\CA), Kerberos, VLANs (IEEE 802.1Q), WINS, DHCP, DNS, OSPF, RIP, RIP2, SIP, RTP, STUN.
- Vendors: Cisco, Sonicwall, Netgear, Zyxel, Ubiquiti, Sophos, Fortinet.

Â

Strong knowledge in OSI model, CIDR, NAT, ACL and network routing.â€⟨ Experience with Copper, Twin-ax and Fiber networking standards.Â

Hardware

- All x86 based technology with a expertise in server technology.
- All x86 based laptops and desktops.
- Installation and configuration of layer 2/3 switches, routers, back-hauls, gateways WIFI and VLANs.Â
- SAN technology including iSCSI and fiber channel.
- All major type of RAIDs and RAID controllers.
- Strong knowledge in technical abilities and limitations of hardware,

Experience

System Engineer/Network Engineer

July 2016 to Current CE Technologies i1/4 City, STATE

- Primary Engineer for Network Infrastructure.
- Top Escalation endpoint for support department.
- Senior server engineer.
- Primary Linux server engineer.
- Auditor of security protocols and other compliance.
- Manager of IT deployments projects.
- VOIP PBX engineering and deployment.
- Researching and developing new procedures and automation.
- Consultant for clients and coworkers.

IT Director / Network Engineer

August 2009 to June 2016 LyteSpeed Computers Inc i $\frac{1}{4}$ City , STATE

- Servicing X86 and X86-64 based Laptops, Desktops and Servers.
- Installation of Router, switches, access points, thinclients, gateways and firewalls.
- Installation of Cat5/6 cable runs with RJ-45 connectors.
- Engineering of IT deployments for business environments.Â
- Primary technician for small/medium business networks including design, optimization and repair.
- Server administrator of multiple mission critical Ubuntu/Windows servers.
- Network engineer in charge of troubleshooting complex low level networking issues.
- Virus and spyware removal on a broad spectrum of operating systems and hardware configurations.
- Developing and testing automation scripting for Windows and Linux environments.
- Managing a group of IT professionals while growing the department.

- Growing a break-fix repair company into a full MSP company with many active clients.
- Maintain relationships with clients and helping them with their technology needs.

EBay Sales Associate

May 2009 to August 2009 Maven Technologies il/4 City , STATE

- Testing and refurbing of used hardware.
- Working In a team environment with common goals.

Education

A.S. Degree : Computer Systems Technology , 2009 Monroe Community College ï1/4 City , State Computer Systems Technology